DAVID ADEDIJI

 $+2348116328749 \diamond Lagos$, Nigeria

davidadediji@gmail.com \lor linkedin.com/in/davidadediji1

PROFILE SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience with speciality in creating, testing and maintaining software components on both Client and Server side. I am proficient in the use of programming languages such as JavaScript(NodeJS), TypeScript and Java. I have expert knowledge of software development lifecycle and agile methodologies. I am also analytical and fast at picking up new technologies.

SKILLS

Languages and Frameworks Javascript, Typescript, Java, SpringBoot, Nodejs(Express), ChakraUI

Databases MongoDB, PostgreSQL,

Tools Git, GitHub, Postman, Docker, AWS Amplify, Jira, Confluence

Soft Skills Pair Programming, Excellent Technical Writing

EXPERIENCE

MaibornWolff GmBH

FullStack Software Engineer

AUGUST 2022 – February 2023

Munich, Germany

- Developed visually stunning frontend applications using React, Chakra UI, and AWS Amplify, resulting in seamless user experience.
- Collaborated with a team to design the database architecture of a construction management app on AWS Amplify, ensuring efficient data management and retrieval.
- Created scalable and secure Rest API endpoints using Java SpringBoot for an internal social interaction tool, ensuring 98% uptime.

Backend / QA (Automation)

FEBRUARY 2021 - JULY 2022

Quabbly Technologies

Lagos, Nigeria

- Built automated behavior-driven tests for company workflows, billing API, and other features with Javascript and Cucumber JS (Gherkins) framework to ensure an uptime of 99%.
- Deployed automated tests to CI/CD (Jenkins, BitBucket pipelines) and monitor during nightly builds.
- Extended Database architectures on MongoDB for Quabbly web application.

Technical Writer

NOVEMBER, 2020 – FEBRUARY, 2021

Quabbly Technologies

Lagos, Nigeria

- Tested internal APIs, then documented them for the engineering team using Postman and confluence.
- Documented new and changing product functionality by analyzing technical and product information from various sources, which helped with fast onboarding.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Write articles and posts relating to software engineering, with few published on Educative io and Dev. to.
- Actively attend community meetups centered around open-source, writing and best developer practices.
- Complete courses related to system design, cloud technologies and software engineering on platforms like Udemy, Educative and Udacity.

EDUCATION

B.Sc Chemistry 2014 - 2019

CGPA: 4.36/5.0

Federal University of Agriculture Abeokuta, Ogun State, Nigeria.